<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   <title>JasonButz.info - Projects</title>
   
   <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info</link>
   <description/>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <atom:link href="http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
   <item>
    <title>Time Track</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/timetracker.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/timetracker.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>At work I was keeping track of my hours using a spreadsheet, but every month or so I would have to adjust the formulas to be able to calculate all of my time. It worked, but wasn’t great. One Friday evening I decided to create a simple one user time tracking app that could run on top of Heroku. Using Sinatra and MongoDB I was able to create a small application that did exactly what I wanted.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>ServiceNow CLI</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/servicenowcli.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/servicenowcli.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I created this small program for two reasons. Firstly to help me learn C#. Secondly to allow me to easily download copies of scripts from Service Now in a format I could use them.
With this program you can download Business Rules and Client Scripts from your ServiceNow instance for any table. I hope to eventually add more functionality.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Sublime Text Glide Completion</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/sublimetest-glide.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/sublimetest-glide.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>While working with ServiceNow it got agravating to not get autocompletions of Glide functions in Sublime Text, so I decided to extend Sublime Text and add that feature.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Redmine Mailstatus</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/redmine-mailstatus.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/redmine-mailstatus.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>This is a small <a href="http://www.redmine.org">Redmine</a> plugin that allows the status of a picket to automatically change when a note is added and the ticket’s status is already at a certain values.
This was my first time working with Ruby on Rails.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Wordpress Admin Bar Manager</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/chrome-wordpress.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 10:09:52 -0500</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/chrome-wordpress.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I created this extension for Google Chrome to help admins of Wordpress sites.
The admin bar is a useful tool, but it gets in the way of screenshots. That is what this extension means to fix.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Laravel Akismet API</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/laravel-akismet.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/laravel-akismet.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>On the old verion of this site I used laravel, and wanted to use Akismet to ensure I didn’t get sent spam. I created this plugin so that I could easily access the Akismet library from within laravel.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Push to Google Drive</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/other/push-drive.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/other/push-drive.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>This script makes use of Google’s APIs to push a CSV file, generated on the server, to a particular user’s account. It is all done with an Administrator’s offline token allowing files to be pushed to any account without the user having to first authorize the transfer. This eased adoption and minimized setup.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Document Graph</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/other/docgraph.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/other/docgraph.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>The Document Graph application was created as a small experiment to visualize the relations between different
documents in the ERP system. The graph was especially interesting when it was generated for a very large rder. 
When the order was finally complete over 500 documents were involved.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Android Demo - Webview</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/android-webview.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/personal/android-webview.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I haven’t had many opportunities to experiment with developing Android applications, so this was a small project I did to learn some of the basics. 
I created it in such a format that it would be flexible enough for someone else to base an application off of in case they so desired. 
It supports viewing web pages packaged within the application or on the Internet, and its behavior can be modified with only a few changes.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
   <item>
    <title>Google Apps Managment Tool</title>
    <link>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/other/gapps-tool.html</link>
    <dc:creator  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Butz</dc:creator>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <guid>http://www.jasonbutz.info/project/other/gapps-tool.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
     <p>The Google Apps for Business Control Panel provides access to many of the feature Google offers for managing a domain, but it does not provide access to all of them. There are a few that can only be accessed via APIs. This tool was made to provide access to the Delegation settings and the Global Contacts settings.</p>

     ]]></description>
   </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>